Guide to the Allegheny Observatory Records, 1850-1977 UA.5.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Administrative Files, 1858-1977; VI.
  - University of Pittsburgh (Western University of Pennsylvania prior to 1909), 1.
    - Five items from N.E. Wagman on the Astronomy Department, 1961 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - Affirmative Action (Box 74, Folder 18)
      - Astronomy 011 Course Evaluations, Fall 1968 (Box 74, Folder 19)
      - Astronomy Lab Manual (Box 74, Folder 20)
      - Intro to Astronomy Lab Manual (Box 74, Folder 21)
      - Astronomy 2 Lab Manual (Box 74, Folder 22)
      - Astronomy Lab Guidelines (Box 74, Folder 23)
      - Astronomy Lecture - George Gatewood (Box 74, Folder 24)
      - Computer Center (Box 74, Folder 25)
      - Core Curriculum (Box 74, Folder 26)
      - Course Proposal, Fall 1972 (Box 74, Folder 27)
      - Course Syllabi (Box 74, Folder 28-29)
      - Department of Astronomy - Demographics, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 30)
      - Department of Astronomy - Statement of Mission (Box 74, Folder 31)
      - Departmental Data (Box 74, Folder 32)
      - Eureka Newsletter (Box 74, Folder 33)
      - Exams (Box 74, Folder 34)
      - Frick Public Evening Program (Box 74, Folder 35)
      - Graduate Student Information (Box 74, Folder 36)
      - The Humanist - "Objections to Astrology" (Box 74, Folder 37)
      - Keyholder Memo (Box 74, Folder 38)
      - Kiewiet de Jonge Planner, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 39)
      - Proposals (Box 74, Folder 41)
      - Seminars (Box 74, Folder 42)
      - Staff - Postcards (Box 74, Folder 43)
      - Teaching: Graduate Students (Box 74, Folder 44)
      - Textbooks (Box 74, Folder 45)
      - Wagman's Annual report notes, July 1962-July 1974 (Box 74, Folder 46)
      - Wagman - Retirement (Box 74, Folder 47)
  - Reports and Minutes, 2.
    - Director's Reports, 1873, 1900-1903, 1909, 1916, 1918-1920, 1938, 1940-1941, 1951-1952, 1964-1969 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Report detailing the duties of the Director, c. 1880 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Various Reports (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Statistics re:visitors, 1909-1956
      - List of Faculty, 1914-1915
      - Report by F. Schlesinger describing observatory, no date
      - Publication for the year ending, June 30, 1917
      - Report from the committee on stellar paid taxes for the year ending, June 30, 1918
      - Inventory of Observatory apparatus, no date
      - Allegheny Parralae Program, no date
    - Minutes of Allegheny Observatory and Telescope Association, May 14, 1858, May 15, 1860, November 12, 1863 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Allegheny Observatory, 1882-1912 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Meetings of the University concerning the Observatory, extracts, 1867-1873, August 23, 1943 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - Annual Fund Giving Report, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 48)
      - Annual Reports, 1967-1976 (Box 74, Folder 49)
      - Faculty Activity Reports, 1972-1988 (Box 74, Folder 50)
      - PPBS, 1969-1973 (Box 74, Folder 51)
      - Measuring Reports, 1967-1969 (Box 74, Folder 52)
  - Building Specifications, 3.
    - General contract work specifications (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Fire proofing (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Plastic work (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Tile and asphalt roofing (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Iron work (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Concrete floors (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Painting and glazing (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Marble work (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Carpenter work (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Metal work (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Typed copy of contract specifications (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - Written draft of contract specifications (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - Map (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - Building dimensions (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - Building estimate (Box 46, Folder 25)
    - Design of Observatory Dark Room (Oversize 26)
    - Plan of Observatory, 1895 (Oversize 27)
    - Plan for an Astro-Physical Observatory, 1892 (Oversize 28)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - Astronomical Laboratory, 1972-1973 (Box 75, Folder 1a-1b)
      - Chancellor Letter on Rennovations, December 10, 1974 (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - City Police, 1974-1975 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - Duquesne Light, 1955 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - Locks Installed, July 14, 1970 (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Astronomy Slides and Photos (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Exterior Lighting (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - Furnishings (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - Lecture Hall (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Riverview Park - Lighitng Improvements (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - Second Floor Alterations (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Thaw Dome (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - Thaw Dome Ice Guards (Box 75, Folder 13)
      - Theiss Documents, 1971-1973 (Box 75, Folder 14-15)
      - Telescopes - 6 inch Brashear Refractor (Box 75, Folder 16)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Telescope Proposal (Box 75, Folder 17)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Comparison Spark (Box 75, Folder 18)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Contracts (Box 75, Folder 19)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Correspondence (Box 75, Folder 20)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Data/Graphs (Box 75, Folder 21)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Drawings (Box 75, Folder 22)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Amplifier (Box 75, Folder 23)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Dew Warning (Box 75, Folder 24)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Mirror (Box 75, Folder 25)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Program Report, 1961 (Box 75, Folder 26)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Observing Procedures (Box 75, Folder 27)
      - Telescopes - Keeler Stiffening Rods (Box 75, Folder 28)
      - Telescopes - Mellon Spectrograph Heat Management (Box 75, Folder 29)
      - Telescopes - Small Astrograph (Box 75, Folder 30)
      - Telescopes - Thaw Telescope Contracts, 1971-1974 (Box 75, Folder 31-33)
      - Telescopes - Thaw Telescope Bids and Reports (Box 75, Folder 34)
      - Telescopes - Thaw Telescope Lens Alignment (Box 75, Folder 35)
      - Telescopes - Thaw Telescope Owens-Illinois Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 75, Folder 36)
      - Telescopes - Thaw Telescope Proposal (Box 75, Folder 37)
      - Telescopes - Hartman Tests (Box 75, Folder 38)
      - Telescopes - Hartman Tests 31" Keeler Telescope (Box 75, Folder 39)
      - Telescopes - Renovation (Box 75, Folder 40)
  - Library, 4.
    - Books and periodicals ordered, 1899-1902 (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - Books and periodicals ordered, 1903-1919 (Box 47, Folder 30)
    - Donations, 1903-1923 (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - List of periodicals holdings, February 6, 1952 (Box 47, Folder 32)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - Allegheny Observatory Library - LS 258 Project (Box 75, Folder 41)
      - Allegheny Observatory Library Renovations (Box 75, Folder 42)
      - Missing Books, August 15, 1974 (Box 75, Folder 43)
  - Allegheny Observatory Committee, 5.
    - Reports to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, 1871 (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - Reports to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, 1900-1907 (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - Minutes, 1898-1901 (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - General Office Files, 6.
    - Budgets, 1867-69 (Box 48, Folder 36)
    - Budgets, 1913-1935 (Box 48, Folder 37)
    - Budgets, 1937-1943 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    - Budgets, 1943-1949 (Box 48, Folder 39)
    - Budgets, 1949-1954 (Box 48, Folder 40)
    - Budgets, 1954-1957 (Box 48, Folder 41)
    - Budgets, 1960-1963 (Box 48, Folder 42)
    - Budgets, 1963-1969 (Box 48, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous receipts, 1873-1909 (Box 48, Folder 44)
    - Cash books, Samuel Langley, 1870-1872, 1876-1881, 1882-1892, 1891-1899 (Box 48, Folder 45)
    - Cash books, Frank Very, 1870, 1871-1875, 1875 (Box 48, Folder 46)
    - Cash books, Frank Very, 1878, 1879-1880, 1880-1881, 1881 (Box 48, Folder 47)
    - Cash books, Frank Very, 1881, 1882, 1882-1883, 1891 (Box 48, Folder 48)
    - Check receipt books, 1883-1887 (Box 48, Folder 49)
    - Check receipt books, 1885-1889 (Box 48, Folder 50)
    - Check receipt books, 1889-1891 (Box 49, Folder 51)
    - Petty Cash books, 1883-1891 (Box 49, Folder 52)
    - Petty Cash books, 1891-1900 (Box 49, Folder 53)
    - Account books, 1905-1914 (Box 49, Folder 54)
    - Account books, 1914-1919 (Box 49, Folder 55)
    - Account books, 1927-1954 (Box 50, Folder 56)
    - Day books, 1870-1879 (Box 50, Folder 57)
    - Day books, 1895-1900 (Box 50, Folder 58)
    - Cash account books, 1880-1882 (Box 50, Folder 59)
    - Cash account books, 1881-1895 (Box 50, Folder 60)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - Budgets, 1969-1972 (Box 75, Folder 44)
      - Budgets, 1972-1973 (Box 75, Folder 45)
      - Budgets, 1973-1974 (Box 75, Folder 46)
      - Budgets, 1974-1975 (Box 75, Folder 47)
      - Budget Summary, 1977 (Box 75, Folder 48)
      - General Office Equipment Corporation (Box 75, Folder 49)
      - Telephone (Box 75, Folder 50)
      - Visitors Register, 1892 (Box 75, Folder 51)
      - Visitors Register, 1911 (Box 75, Folder 52)
  - William Thaw File, 7.
    - Letters to Thaw
      - Brashear, John A. (Astronomical and Physical Instrument Works, Allegheny, PA), September 19, 1887, April 7, 1891 (Box 51, Folder 61)
      - Carnahan R. B. (Board of Trustees, Western University of Pennsylvania, February 13, 1885-August 19, 1885
      - Goff, M.B. (Chancellor, Western University of Pennsylvania), December 30, 1872
      - Gray, D.S. (Union Railroad and Transportation Company, Columbus, Ohio), December 4, 1871
      - Griggs, Joseph F. (Western University of Pennsylvania), August 4, 1890
      - Holland William J. (Chancellor, Western University of Pennsylvania), April 14, 1891-January 27, 1894
      - Keeler, James E. (Director, Allegheny Observatory, before 1892 of Lick Observatory, Mount Hamilton, CA), July 31, 1890-March 12, 1891, January 6, 1894 (Box 51, Folder 62)
      - Kerr, C.U. (Western University of Pennsylvania), August 11, 1890
      - Koons, C.H. (Union Lane, Baltimore), February 28, 1879
      - Laying, J.D. (various railroad companies, Pittsburgh), November 29, 1871-May 13, 1873
      - Scott, James B. (Pittsburgh), July 24, 1890 (Box 51, Folder 63)
      - Smith, Edmund (Pennsylvania Rail Road Company, Philadelphia), October 24, 1870
      - United States Chief Signal Officer (S.M. Mills), October 4, 1883
      - Very, Frank W. (Allegheny Observatory), January 14, 1890-May 2, 1891
    - Letters from Thaw
      - Cassat, A.J. (Pennsylvania Railroad, Philadelphia), May 26, 1870, April 17, 1882 (Box 51, Folder 64)
      - Carnahan, R.B. (Board of Trustees, Western University of Pennsylvania), October 9, 1884
      - Emerson, R.H., May 7, 1885
      - King, Josah and C. Hussey, May 15, 1872
      - Layng, J.D. (various railroad companies, Pittsburgh), November 27, 1871-May 31, 1873
      - Correspondence record, no date (Box 51, Folder 65)
      - Personal property at Observatory, no date (Box 51, Folder 66)
      - Principal observatory instruments, no date (Box 51, Folder 67)
- Observation, 1869-1930; VII.
  Series VII contains measurements, notebooks, journals, wastebooks, drawings, and yearbooks of observations recorded at the Allegheny Observatory arranged by astronomer.
  - Notebooks, 1.
    - Samuel Langley
      - Longitude, 2 volumes (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
      - Spectroscopy (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Wastebook, 1876-1880 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - F.L.O. Wadsworth
      - Astronomy and Geodesy (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Chemical Physics (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Chemistry (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Civil Engineering (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Daily Journal (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - Elliptic Functions, Theory of (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Field Book (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - Functions, Theories of (Box 54, Folder 12)
      - Hydraulics (Box 54, Folder 13)
      - Laboratory Notebook (Box 54, Folder 14)
      - Lunar Host (Box 55, Folder 15)
      - Mathematics (Box 55, Folder 16)
      - Mechanism (Box 55, Folder 17)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 55, Folder 18)
      - National Academy of Arts and Sciences, Proceedings of Observations (Box 55, Folder 19)
      - Physics (Box 55, Folder 20-21)
      - Physics Laboratory (Box 55, Folder 22-23)
      - Prisms, Measuremnet of (Box 55, Folder 24)
      - Science and Engineering, Reference List of Papers (Box 55, Folder 25)
      - Specific Light (Box 55, Folder 26)
      - Theoretical Optics (Box 55, Folder 27)
      - Thermometer, Calibration of (Box 56, Folder 28)
      - Untitled Notebook, no date (Box 56, Folder 29)
      - Unititled Notebook, 1901 (Box 56, Folder 30)
    - Frank Schlesinger and Frank Jordan
      - Unititled Notebook, 1909-1913 (Box 56, Folder 31)
    - Frank Jordan
      - Orbit of 18 aquile (Box 56, Folder 32)
      - Orbit of lyrae (Box 57, Folder 33)
      - Orbit of orrons (Box 57, Folder 34)
      - Orbit of serpentis (Box 58, Folder 35)
      - Radical Velocity of 25 stars (Box 58, Folder 36)
      - Records, 1884-1930 (Box 59, Folder 37)
      - Spectrographic observations of parsel (Box 59, Folder 38)
    - Robert Baker
      - Observations, 1907-1908 (Box 60, Folder 39)
      - Observations, 1908-1909 (Box 60, Folder 40)
    - William Scaife
      - 1873 (Box 61, Folder 41)
    - Level Notebooks
      - December 1868-August 1872 (Box 61, Folder 42)
      - August 1872-May 1878 (Box 61, Folder 43)
      - June 1878-August 1884 (Box 61, Folder 44)
      - August 1884-August 1892 (Box 61, Folder 45)
    - Observatory Notebooks
      - C.L. Parker, July 1870-January 1872 (Box 61, Folder 46-47)
      - Samuel S. Strassner and A.E. Frost, January 1872-December 1872 (Box 61, Folder 48)
      - A.E. Frost, January 1873-January 1874 (Box 61, Folder 49)
      - A.E. Frost, March 1874-December 1875 (Box 61, Folder 50-51)
      - A.E. Frost and R.F. Hall, July 1876-January 1877 (Box 61, Folder 52)
    - Wastebooks
      - James Keeler, 1881-1882 (Box 61, Folder 53)
      - Alfred B. Selir, 1883 (Box 61, Folder 54)
      - James Page, 1887-1888 (Box 61, Folder 55-56)
    - Yearbooks
      - 1869-1884 (Box 62, Folder 57-72)
      - 1885-1891 (Box 63, Folder 73-79)
      - 1892-1900 (Box 64, Folder 80-88)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Address Books (Box 65, Folder 89-91)
      - Character of the Defractory at the Focus of a Telescope (Box 65, Folder 92)
      - Constants (Box 65, Folder 93)
      - Heat Book (Box 65, Folder 94)
      - Least Squares (Box 65, Folder 95)
      - Miscellany (Box 65, Folder 96)
      - Optical Notes (Box 65, Folder 97)
      - Photography (Box 65, Folder 98)
      - Photometric Observations (Box 65, Folder 99)
      - Time by Single Altitudes of the Sun (Box 65, Folder 100)
      - Unititled (Box 65, Folder 101-105)
      - Unititled (Box 66, Folder 106-107)
  - Drawings, 2.
    - Sunspots
      - February 1873-December 1876 (Box 67, Folder 108)
      - January 1877-December 1880, 1882 (Box 68, Folder 109)
      - A Typical Sunspot, December 23-24, 1873 (Box 69, Folder 110)
      - Untitled Drawing by Langley, 1873 (Oversize 111)
      - Original Pencil Drawing, March 5-7, 1873 (Oversize 112)
      - Original Pencil Drawing, December 24, 1873 (Oversize 112, Folder 113)
    - Mars
      - Drawings of Mars and of Schiaparalli Globe showing Opposition of 1892, by James Keeler (Oversize 112, Folder 114)
      - Outline Drawing of Mars, by Keeler, August 17-September 17, 1892 (Oversize 115)
    - Jupiter
      - Circle Cut to Scale with the Dimensions of Jupiter Written, no date (Oversize 115, Folder 116)
      - Copy of Professor Keeler's Drawings of September 17, 1891, by Frank Schlesinger, no date (Oversize 117)
    - Saturn
      - Circle Cut Outs to Scale of Saturn and her Rings with Dimensions Written, no date (Oversize 117, Folder 118)
- Graphic Materials, 1878-1910; VIII.
  - Mechanical Drawings, 1.
    - Samuel Langley
      - Design for an Integrating A[?] Nets, 1886 (Oversize 1)
      - Sketch of Whirling Table for Flying Tests, from Langley Letterbook #3
      - Sifting Train, Solar Lunar Spectrum, Figure 1
      - Illustrating Principal of Transformation of Information from the Prismatic to the Normal Spectrum
      - The Infra-Red Solar Spectrum of a 60 Rock-Salt Prism
    - F.W. Very
      - State of the Sky, 1878-1879
      - Curve d=f(2) for the Hastings Rock Salt Prism
      - Curves Showing the Effect of Atmospheric Absorption on the Distribution of Energy in the Spectrum of the Higher Prism
    - J.E. Keeler
      - Sketch of a Design for a Star Spectroscope for the 36-inch Equatorial of the Lick Observatory
    - John A. Brashear
      - Alt-Arimuth Mounting for 6 1/2" Comet Seeker, 1887
    - F.L.O. Wadsworth
      - Various Designs for Telescopes
    - Frank Schlesinger
      - Various Designs for Telescopes; Maps of the Gulf Coast Comet of 1907 and Halley's Comet of 1910, Ursa Major, and Mt. Whitney
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - 13" Telescope Diagrams (Box 75, Folder 53)
      - Console (Box 75, Folder 54)
      - Drawings (Box 75, Folder 55)
      - Electrical (Box 75, Folder 56)
      - Telescope (Box 75, Folder 57)
      - Thaw Console (Box 75, Folder 58)
      - Thaw Shutter (Box 75, Folder 59)
  - Notes and Research (New Material Added, 2013), 2.
    - "Barnard's Star" - Peter Van de Kamp, 1975 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Cards - Catalogues (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Celestial Mechanics (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Colloquium Notes, 1969-1970 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Consultation - Notes (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Dante (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Spectroscopic Orbit (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Drafts and Scraps (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Error Theory (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Material taken from file called "First Drafts" (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Focal Curve of Thaw Telescope (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Graphs on Curvature (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - IGY Satellite (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Kapteyn-Van Rhijn equation (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Keeler Telescope - Thermal Response (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Mellon Spectrograph - Focal Plane (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Mellon Spectrograph - Line Curvature (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Membrane Problem (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Navigation (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Material from file entitled "Old Measuring Engine" (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Optics (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Plate Information and Records, 1900-1934 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Reductions - Spectrograph (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - Sensitometer, 1962 (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - Small Brashear Measuring Engine - notes and measurements (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - Sunspot Numbers, 1953-1975 (Box 76, Folder 26)
- Publicity, 1893-1902; IX.
  - News Releases, 1893-1902 (Box 70, Folder 1)
- News Clippings (Miscellaneous), 1907-1947; X.
  - 1907-1947 (Box 70, Folder 2)
- Scrapbooks, 1873-1917; XI.
  - Contains Newsclippings on Langley, 1873-1898 (Oversize 1)
  - Commonplace Book, 1895-1917 (Oversize 2)
- Organizations and Societies, 1899-1960; XII.
  - Astronomical Society of Pittsburgh, 1.
    - Constitution (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
    - Checkbook (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
  - American Astronomical Society, 2.
    - Minutes of the Council (President's Copy), 1899-1917 (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1936-1939 (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
    - Programs of Meetings, 1912, 1937-1941 (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
    - Meeting at Pittsburgh, April 18-21, 1960 (Oversize 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1960 (Oversize 2, Folder 9-11)
    - Lectures, Radio Astronomy (Oversize 2, Folder 12)
    - Lectures, Sub-Dwarf Stars (Oversize 2, Folder 13)
    - Financial Information (Oversize 2, Folder 14)
  - National Science Foundation, 2013; 3.
    New Material Added, 2013
    - NSF Proposal, December, 1954 (Box 76, Folder 28)
      Kiewiet de Jonge, Joost H. "Application for a Grant for Scientific Research in Astronomy". December, 1954
    - NSF Proposal, January, 1955 (Box 76, Folder 29)
      Wagman, N.E. "Application for a Grant to Provide Quipment for the Observation and Study of Spectroscopic Binaries at the Allegheny Observatory". January, 1955
    - NSF Proposal, November, 1956 (Box 76, Folder 30)
      Wagman, N.E. "Application for a Grant to Provide Equipment for the Observation and Study of Spectroscopic Binaries at the Allegheny Observatory". November, 1956.
    - NSF Final Reports on Grants G-2372 and G-3948, 1956 (Box 76, Folder 31)
    - NSF Proposals, 1961,1965,1966,1968 (Box 76, Folder 32)
      Kieweiet de Jonge, Joost H. "Application for a Grant to Provide Equipment and to Support Additional Personel Needed in the Study of Spectroscopic Binaries at the Allegheny Observatory". August,1961.
      Wagman, N.E. "Application for a Grant to Support the Observation and Study of Spectroscopic and Astrometric Binaries at Allegheny Observatory". November, 1965.
      Wagman, N.E. "Application for a Grant to Support a Continuation of the Program of Observation and Study of Spectroscopic and Astrometric Binaries at the Allegheny Observatory". December, 1966.
      Wagman, N.E. "Application for a Grant to Support a Continuation of the Program of Observation and Study of Spectroscopic and Astrometric Binaries at the Allegheny Observatory". March, 1968.
    - NSF Proposals, 1968 - 1971 (Box 76, Folder 33)
      Wagman, N.E. "Application for a Grant to Support a Continuation of the Program of Observation and Study of Spectroscopic and Astrometric Binaries at the Allegheny Observatory". April, 1970.
    - NSF Proposal, March 12,1973 (Box 76, Folder 34)
      Kiewiet de Jonge, Joost H. "A Proposal to Help Support a New Effort to Significantly Improve Existing and Future Allgeheny Parallaxes, Sept. 1, 1973 - Aug. 31, 1974". March 12, 1973.
    - NSF Final Reports, 197-1969 (Box 76, Folder 35)
  - Extrasolar Planetary Foundation, 4.
    New Material Added, 2013. First meeting in 1980, the Extrasolar Planetary Foundation was led by George Gatewood, director of the Allegheny Observatory. As a non-profit organizaton, it's goal was to "promote, foster, sponsor and support astronomical research in the detection and study of extrasolar plnatery systems." Today it remains focused on these same goals.
    - Extrasolar Planetary Foundation - Goals, By Laws, Minutes, Agendas (Box 76, Folder 36)
    - Extrasolar Planetary Foundation - Correspondence (Box 76, Folder 37)
    - Extrasolar Planetary Foundation - Press Releases, Publicity (Box 76, Folder 38)
    - Extrasolar Planetary Foundation - Memos (Box 76, Folder 39)
    - Extrasolar Planetary Foundation - Finances (Box 76, Folder 40)
  - Other Organizations, 5.
    - National Research Council Questionaire (Box 76, Folder 27)
    - IAU BE Star Cooperation, 1961-1962 (Box 76, Folder 41)
    - Amatuer Astronomers Association of Pittsburgh (Box 76, Folder 42)
    - U.S. Naval Observatory - Allegheny Observatory Use Agreement (Box 76, Folder 43)
    - U.S. Naval Observatory - Observatory Questionaire (Box 76, Folder 44)
    - Pittsburgh Bicentennial Commision (Box 76, Folder 45)
    - Baldwin-Whitehall School District (Box 76, Folder 46)
- Publications, 1870-1975; XIII.
  - Monographs, 1.
    - Oxford University Examination Responses, James Parker and Co.: London, Trinity Term, 1870 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Annals of the Astronomical Observatory of Harvard College, vol.3, John Wilson Son; Cambridge, MA, 1876 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - "Researches on Solar Heat and Its Absorption by the Earth's Atmoshphere" (Box 71, Folder 47)
        Bibliography
        Langley, Samuel Pierpoint. Researches on Solar Heat and its Absoprtion by the Earth's Atmosphere. A Report of the Mount Whitney Expedition. Government Printing Press; Washington. 1884.
  - Pamphlets, 2.
    - Computing, Pamphlets and Catalogs on Computing Machines, 1906-1939 (Box 72, Folder 3-7)
    - Optical Equipment, Pamphlets and Catalogs, 1910-1939 (Box 72, Folder 8-13)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - American Design Components 3-72 Guidebook (Box 72, Folder 48)
      - Astro-Mechanics Inc. (Box 72, Folder 49)
      - Boller-Chivens (Box 72, Folder 50-51)